Matthew Curran

Email: five3183@gmail.com

Github: github.com/five3183 | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-curran-tech

Portfolio: www.matthewcurran.tech

Summary

Recent coding bootcamp graduate with a new-found passion for building web applications. Over 10 years of professional experience. Proven history of technical mastery as an Infantry Fire Team Leader, Auto Adjuster and Assistant Manager. Background education in psychology, developed critical thinking, reasoning and problem-solving skills. Talented in handling multiple projects while exceeding quality standards. Seeks an entry level position as a junior developer.

Technical Skills

• HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ajax, Express, Node, MySQL, Mongo, Handlebars, React, GIT, GitHub

Education

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT | SEP 2018 | UNC CHARLOTTE

• An intensive 6-month program dedicated to designing and building web applications.

B.S. PSYCHOLOGY | MAY 2012 | SAINT THOMAS AQUINAS COLLEGE

- Psi Chi Honor Society
- 3.78 GPA

A.A. LIBERAL ARTS | MAY 2010 | ROCKLAND COMMUNITY COLLEGE

- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
- 3.9 GPA

Applications Built

PERSONAL PERSCRIPTION PLANNER

- This app is designed to track user medications and alert them via text message to take them. After adding a medication to your prescription list, the app will query a drug database and check for possible conflicts. Text message alerts will be sent to the user to remind them to take medications.
- This is a react app, with a node.js/express server and uses mongo for the database. Twilio api is used to send text messages and newsapi.org is used for the news feed. NPM packages include axios, moment, bcryptjs, cheerio, cron, dotenv, mongoose, passport, and validator.
- Website: https://presonal-prescription-planner.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/taw1313/team-merge-p3

NOPE!

- This is app allows users to add restaurants to the map, write reviews and update busy status. Icons on the map will be displayed in either red or green depending on the busy status of the restaurant.
- This is a multi-page app that has an node.js/express server and uses mongo for a database. The map canvas and the geocoding is powered by google api.
- Website: https://frozen-plateau-24963.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/five3183/NOPE2.0

THE CLICKY GAME

- This is a game where the player is to select a unique image. After every selection the images will shuffle. Clicking on the same image twice will end the game. Select 12 unique images in a row to win.
- This is a react app.
- Website: https://calm-bastion-93483.herokuapp.com
- GitHub: https://github.com/five3183/clicky

Experience

INSIDE AUTO ADJUSTER | ALLSTATE INSURANCE COMPANY | 2015 - 2018

Negotiated, assessed and compiled auto repair estimates. Efficiently handled 8 to 11 auto claims per day. Trained employees on standard operating procedures computer usage and new technologies. Periodically lead team meetings. Continually exceeded quality goals by 5% and production goals by 25%.

ASSITANT MANAGER | B&B AUTO BODY | 2009 - 2014

Tracked vehicles repairs ensuring low repair cycle time. Performed quality control checks during and after repairs. Ensured that proper repair methods were being followed. Assembled and disassembled vehicles. Used scan tools to diagnose, and clear trouble codes.

INFANTRY FIRE TEAM LEADER | US ARMY | 2004 - 2009

Alpha team leader responsible for a 4-person fire team and maintenance and accountability of all team equipment. Lead combat patrols during Operation Iraqi Freedom. Subject matter expert on all assigned weapon systems. Combat Infantry and Expert Infantry Badge recipient.